urbanthreads.com 2018-03-24

# Privacy Policy | Urban Threads: Unique and Awesome Embroidery Designs

Urban Threads Privacy Policy 

This Privacy Policy applies to [www.urbanthreads.com](http://www.urbanthreads.com/), which is owned and operated by Urban Threads. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect and use the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. 

**Urban Threads** has created this privacy policy to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy and our pledge to keep your personal information secure. The following is information that **Urban Threads** gathers and uses:

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement,you should first contact us at [support@urbanthreads.com](mailto:support@urbanthreads.com) (or use the online [Contact Urban Threads form](http://www.urbanthreads.com/form_contact) at www.urbanthreads.com)

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request. 

**Registration**

**Urban Threads** requires that shoppers register with an email address and original password. The email address is required so that we can contact you about designs that you have purchased. A password is necessary for shoppers to access the products that they've purchased, and to use the unique and personal parts of the site, such as profile page, list of faves, and past purchases. 

Shoppers at **Urban Threads** are assured that their email address, name, and password are kept private and secure and are not sold, exchanged, or traded with any third party. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. 

Your information shall be retained for as long as your account is active. If you wish to cancel your account please contact us at [ support@urbanthreads.com](mailto:support@urbanthreads.com). We will retain your information as necessary to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. 

After registration, shoppers will receive a confirmation email with their email address registered on the site that they can keep for their records. 

**Tracking Technologies**

Urban Threads and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service. To manage Flash cookies, please click here:[Flash Player.](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html)

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

**Log Files**

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. 

**Urban Threads** has the ability to track and record IP addresses. This information is not shared or given to any third party. It's used to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer the Web site. We run reports that show how many visitors come to our site each day, which parts of the world visitors are coming from, and which Web browsers are most popular with our visitors. 

No personal information (name or email address) links any visitor to any automatically collected data. All the data that is gathered is used for the sole purpose of improving our Web site and products, and is not shared with anyone else. 

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button, the Twitter button, etc. that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**Blog / Forum**

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blog. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, contact us at [support@urbanthreads.com](mailto:support@urbanthreads.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

**Testimonials/Reviews**

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our website in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [support@urbanthreads.com](mailto:support@urbanthreads.com). 

**Promotional Mailings and Newsletters**

Email newsletters are sent every Friday with information about new designs and projects. 

All shoppers can choose not to receive weekly updates by filling out the [ Contact Urban Threads](http://www.urbanthreads.com/form_contact) form at the Web site, or by replying to one of the promotional emails and requesting to be removed from the mailing list. 

**Ordering**

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities. For example, we use a secure third party to process credit cards. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

**Urban Threads** uses a shopping basket/order form for shoppers to purchase products. Shoppers may pay for an order via PayPal, or using a Visa, MasterCard, or Discover credit card. The site collects billing and financial information (credit card numbers and security codes). Financial information that is collected is used only to bill the shopper for the products requested. This information is used only for that purpose, and is never shared with any other person or company. No credit card information is stored in your profile or in any other area of the site other than the data legally required by the credit card companies. 

If a shopper wishes to purchase a gift certificate for someone else, we'll ask for the name and email address of the person getting the certificate. This information is used to send an email to the person to notify them of the certificate code. Urban Threads stores this information for the purpose of sending this one-time email and maintaining the gift certificate information assigned to the recipient.   
Your friend may contact us at [support@urbanthreads.com](mailto:support@urbanthreads.com) to request that we remove this information from our database. 

**Links**

**Urban Threads** contains links to other Web sites. **Urban Threads** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the other Web sites. As privacy practices may vary at other sites, please review each site's privacy policy. 

**Security**

**Urban Threads** has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alternation of your personal information under our control. The security certificate is provided by [GoDaddy](http://www.godaddy.com/). There is a seal of authenticity at **Urban Threads** and on the purchasing page. Click on the seals for additional information about the security certificate. 

**Urban Threads** uses secure socket layer technology (SSL) to encrypt and transmit sensitive information. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

**Correcting and Changing Personal Information**

Upon request Urban Threads will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your personal information changes or if you no longer desire our service, you can change or delete any personal information retained at the site with one of these methods: 

  * Complete the [Contact Urban Threads](http://www.urbanthreads.com/contactus.aspx) form at **UrbanThreads.com** and advise us of what to change. 
  * Sign in to **UrbanThreads.com** and edit your personal profile 

We will repond within a reasonable timeframe. 

**Updates and Changes**

**Urban Threads** reserves the right to modify this privacy policy at any time. If we make any material changes to the privacy policy, we'll post a notice on the home page of this website. We'll also advise you how the change affects you, so you are aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances (if any) we disclose it. 

We'll also mention any significant and upcoming changes in an email at least 30 days in advance of the changes. At that time, if you wish to remove or amend any information that is stored at UrbanThreads.com, you may do so. Instructions for removing or amending information will be included in the email sent to you. 

**Contacting Urban Threads**

If you have any questions about the privacy policy or need to contact us, please use the following methods: 

Complete the [Contact Urban Threads](http://www.urbanthreads.com/form_contact) form (link on the left side of **UrbanThreads.com** ) 

Send a letter to:

Urban Threads  
5000 Cheshire Pkwy N # 3  
Minneapolis, MN 55446 

**Legal Disclaimer**

In certain situations, Urban Threads may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We make every effort to preserve user privacy, but we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, such as comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or similar legal process wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. 

If Urban Threads is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

**Effective and Revision Date**

This privacy policy was last updated on April 17, 2017.
